STEFANO CASTRO TOGNINI

Oak Ridge National Laboratory

@ togninis@ornl.gov

+1 (865) 341 0453

stognini

in stognini

I have a Ph.D. in Physics, focused on High Energy Physics (HEP). Currently a Research Associate at Oak Ridge National Laboratory mainly working on *Celeritas*, a GPU Monte Carlo (MC) particle transport code for HEP experiments that will enable the use of DOE's Leadership Computing Facilities (LCFs) in HEP computing workflows. In the past I was a collaborator working on two experiments known as MINOS and NOνA, managed by Fermi National Accelerator Laboratory (Fermilab). These are long-term multi-million dollar endeavors built to understand the nature of neutrinos and answer fundamental questions related to astrophysics, dark matter, and more. My 7+ years of experience, working with diversified teams, led to many published data analyses, all developed using C++, Python, ROOT, shell scripting, massive parallel computing, and MC simulations. Software development is managed using version control (GIT/SVN), allied with automated code referencing (Doxygen). Production of technical documentation is routinely done. Finally, I have experience with teaching at undergraduate level, mentoring graduate students, presenting findings at international conferences, as well as participating in science outreach events.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Research Associate

HPC Methods for Nuclear Applications Group Nuclear Energy and Fuel Cycle Division Oak Ridge National Laboratory

2019 - Present

Oak Ridge (TN), U.S.

COLLABORATIONS

Celeritas Project

github.com/celeritas-project

2020 - Present

♀ ORNL

Core member of the Celeritas development team.

URL Muon Detector Project

♀ ORNL

Core team member involved with all stages of the project: detector design, simulation, commissioning, deployment, and analysis.

NO ν **A Experiment**

novaexperiment.fnal.gov

2013 − 2018

- **♀** Fermilab / ANL / UFG
- Leading author of a published data analysis: PRD 99 122004.
- Integrated a Monte Carlo package with the Fermilab computing framework that is being used by two other experiments at Fermilab and CERN.
- Commissioned/maintained a Remote Operation Center (ROC) at UFG.
- Hardware work that consisted in testing the quality of Avalanche Photo Diodes before being installed in the NOνA Near Detector.

MINOS Experiment

www-numi.fnal.gov

2011 - Present

- **♀** Fermilab / ANL / UFG
- Worked in 2 published data analyses: PRD 91 112006 / PRD 93 052017.
- Wrote documentation for commissioning and certifying ROCs.
- Installed and maintained the MINOS Main Operation Center at Fermilab.
- Built, documented, and maintained a MINOS ROC at UFG.

SCIENTIFIC PUBLICATIONS

SOFT SKILLS

Teaching (3 yrs) Mentoring (4 yrs)

Scientific outreach Public speaking

Portuguese (native)
English
Italian
French

HARD SKILLS

Technical skills

Data structuring Parallel computing

Data analysis Monte Carlo simulation

Programming & scripting languages

C/C++ Python SQL Shell LATEX

Frameworks, libraries, databases, & tools

Fermilab ART Framework GIT Geant4

EDUCATION

ROOT

Ph.D. in Physics - High Energy Physics

Doxygen

Federal University of Goias

CORSIKA

Funding: CAPES, CNPq, ANL

≅ 2012 − 2018

♀ Goiania (GO), Brazil

TORQUE

DOE OSTI www.osti.gov/biblio/1468447 iNSPIRE HEP inspirehep.net/record/1692030

M.Sc. in Physics - High Energy Physics

Federal University of Goias

Funding: CAPES, Fermilab

2010 − 2012

♀ Goiania (GO), Brazil

B.Sc. in Physics

Federal University of Goias

2005 − 2010

♀ Goiania (GO), Brazil